Guide to the Office of the University Registrar Records, 1853 - 2000
Duke University. University Archives
- Subject files, 1946-1988
  - Clark R. Cahow, 1953-1988
    - Financial aid: reports: Peat, Marwick, Mitchell and Co., 1981-1982 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: scholarships: Emma A. Sheafer Drama Scholarship, 1983-1984 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: scholarships: Faculty Scholarship Endowment Fund, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: scholarships: Mark D. MacFarlane Scholarship Fund, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: scholarships: Reginaldo R. Howard Memorial Scholarship, 1979-1985 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: Resident Advisor's Scholarship Program, 1982-1983 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: selective service regulations, 1983 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: statistics, 1984 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: systems study, 1982 (Box 26)
    - Financial aid: undergraduate resources, 1979-1982 (Box 27)
    - Financial aid: University student loans, 1980-1982 (Box 27)
    - Freshman Advisory program, 1970 (Box 27)
    - Functional Mathematics program, 1958 (Box 27)
    - Graduate School (2 folders), 1968-1981 (Box 27)
    - Joint Conference on Institutional Research and Data Processing, 1970 (Box 27)
    - Law School, 1980 (Box 27)
    - Legislative Research Commission to the General Assembly: report on Mental Health, 1973 (Box 27)
    - Louis Calder Foundation, 1977 (Box 27)
    - Management Information Systems Council of the Eight Universities, 1973-1975 (Box 27)
    - Management Information Systems in Higher Education (MISHE): Selected Problems and Solutions, 1970 (Box 27)
    - Medical School (2 folders), 1967-1982 (Box 27)
    - Medical School: admissions system, 1966-1969 (Box 27)
    - Medical School: curriculum, 1967-1969 (Box 27)
    - Medical school: Deans record card, 1970-1971 (Box 27)
    - Minority enrollments, 1977-1978 (Box 27)
    - Mohammed M'Rabet, 1968-1972 (Box 27)
    - National Association of College Deans and Registrars, 1971 (Box 27)
    - 25th Annual National Conference on Higher Education, 1970 (Box 27)
    - National Enrollment Statistics, 1958-1959 (Box 27)
    - NCAA Rules and Regulations, 1985 (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Association of Academic Deans meeting, 1971 (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Board of Higher Education, 1972 (Box 27)
    - North Carolina Regional Medical Program: Regional Advisory Group (4 folders), 1971-1975 (Box 27)
    - North Carolina State Contractual Scholarship for Needy North Carolinians (SCSF), 1977 (Box 27)
    - Office Staff, 1976 (Box 27)
    - Organization charts (proposed), 1976 (Box 27)
    - Permanent records: problems, 1955-1967 (Box 27)
    - Personnel Policy Committee (4 folders), 1979-1981 (Box 27)
    - Physician's Assistant and Radiological Health programs, 1970 (Box 27)
    - Planning proposal: Duke University Year in Action, 1971 (Box 27)
    - Preceptorials, 1973 (Box 28)
    - Pre-registration: review, 1984 (Box 28)
    - President's Council on Black Affairs, 1976 (Box 28)
    - Proposal for a Change in Procedures to Develop a Teaching Schedule, 1969-1970 (Box 28)
    - Provost's Task Force on Physical Education and Recreation, 1974 (Box 28)
    - Registrar's office: external office reviews, 1980-1982 (Box 28)
    - Registrar's office: job descriptions, 1965-1968 (Box 28)
    - Registration: changes in procedures, 1975 (Box 28)
    - Registration: procedures, 1957-1975 (Box 28)
    - Report to President, 1970-1972 (Box 28)
    - Reports, 1960-1968 (Box 28)
    - Restructured times of periods, 1970 (Box 28)
    - Room scheduling, 1975-1982 (Box 28)
    - Scholarships, 1983 (Box 28)
    - School of Nursing: transfer students, 1981 (Box 28)
    - Secondary School Counselors Conference, 1971 (Box 28)
    - Selective Service system, 1966-1973 (Box 28)
    - Special students, 1963-1971 (Box 28)
    - Student Budget study, 1976-1978 (Box 28)
    - Student Budget study, 1982 (Box 28)
    - Student Health Insurance, 1972-1982 (Box 28)
    - Student judicial system, 1972-1975 (Box 28)
    - Ad Hoc Student Records Committee, 1975 (Box 28)
    - Student records: policy, 1967 (Box 28)
    - Studies, 1970-1971 (Box 28)
    - Summer Session Advisory Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 28)
    - Summer Session Advisory Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 28)
    - Summer Transitional Program, 1967-1979 (Box 28)
    - Supplemental Education Opportunity Grant (SEOG), 1983-1986 (Box 28)
    - Ten Universities, 1979-1980 (Box 28)
    - Triangle Universities Computation Center (TUCC), 1969 (Box 28)
    - Undergraduate course load distributions, 1974-1976 (Box 28)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences (UFCAS): Budget Study subcommittee, 1977-1978 (Box 28)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences: Committee on Admissions and Financial Aid (7 folders), 1973-1979 (Box 28)
    - Undergraduate Faculty Council of Arts and Sciences: Committee on Admissions and Financial Aid, 1985-1986 (Box 29)
    - United Health Services: Drug Information Center and Drug Training Center Proposal, 1973 (Box 29)
    - University Commission on the Uses of Technology in Education, 1974-1975 (Box 29)
    - University Committee on Planning and Development, 1958-1960 (Box 29)
    - University Committee on Undergraduate Admissions and Financial Aid (3 folders), 1983-1985 (Box 29)
    - University Schedule Committee (12 folders), 1970-1982 (Box 29)
    - Woman's College, 1956-1966 (Box 29)
    - Work study, 1974 (Box 29)
    - Xeroxing: monthly reports, 1980-1982 (Box 29)
  - Unprocessed Subject Files, circa 1950-1990
    - (Box 39)
      Subjects include the Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, circa 1952-1965 and Statistics, 1970-1971.
    - (Box 40)
      Subjects include Personnel, Conferences, and Committees, circa 1954-1967.
    - (Box 41)
      Subjects include Correspondence and Advanced Placement Students, circa 1950-1965.
    - (Box 42)
      Subjects include Admissions and Financial Aid, circa 1975-1979.
    - (Box 43)
      Subjects include Admissions, circa 1978-1986, and Budget, circa 1966-1975.
    - (Box 44)
      Curriculum Committee, 1971-1984.
    - (Box 45)
      Subjects include Curriculum Subcommittee, 1970-1971, and Committee on Undergraduate Instruction, 1968-1969.
    - (Box 46)
      Subjects include Admissions and Financial Aid, circa 1972-1985.
    - (Box 47)
      Subjects include Educational Facilities Committee, 1973-1987, Budget, 1961-1965, Consortium on Financing Higher Education (COFHE), circa 1980, and general files, circa 1965.
    - (Box 48)
      COFHE, circa 1975-1986.
    - (Box 49)
      COFHE, circa 1978-1984.
    - (Box 50)
      Includes Duke University Building Schematics, 1969.
- Statistics, 1925-1999
  This series consists of statistical information kept on student admissions, enrollment, and grade performance at Duke University since 1925. Categories of statistics found in the earlier years (1925-1963) include geographical distribution of students; religious/denominational distribution; fraternity and sorority averages; class enrollment figures and projections; grade distributions; enlisted men, civilians, and veterans statistics; Quality Point statistics; degrees awarded; and withdrawals. Records during these years are divided either by year or semester and make up the bulk of the series.
  Beginning in 1967-1968, the Registrar's office began printing an Annual Statistical Report containing some of the above categories, including enrollment statistics, geographic distribution, and withdrawals. These reports were distributed publicly and do not fall under the 25 year administrative restriction. By 1980 the Annual Report included tables that break down the international student population by country at the undergraduate and graduate level.
  A large amount of duplicated material was removed from the records. Also removed were many lists of students containing addresses, grade point averages, and ID numbers. Occasionally, these lists have been retained when cumulative statistics did not account for them (for example, lists of international students were kept).
  - Statistics, 1925-1948 (Box 30)
  - Statistics, 1948-1969 (Box 31)
  - Statistics, 1969-1999 (Box 32)
  - Class Census Reports (6 folders), 1932-1943 (Box 36)
  - Departmental Course Correlations (2 folders), 1936-1941 (Box 36)
  - Grade Reports (8 folders), 1938-1940 (Box 36)
  - Grade Reports (6 folders), 1940-1941 (Box 37)
  - Book of students withdrawing from the WWII period, 1941-1943 (Box 18)
  - NC State Board of Higher Education, 1963-1969 (Box 37)
  - Government Reports (12 folders), 1959-1976 (Box 37)
  - North Carolina Higher Education Data Survey (NCHED) (11 folders), 1977-1988 (Box 38)
  - Higher Education Generational Information Survey (HEGIS) (17 folders), 1977-1988 (Box 38)
  - Higher Education Generational Information Survey (HEGIS) degrees awarded, 1986 (Box 38)
  - Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPED) (12 folders), 1986-1987 (Box 38)
- Official Schedule of Courses, 1932-2000
  The official schedule of courses for semesters and summer school are contained within this series. An item-level inventory of the schedules from 1932-1977 is included at the beginning of the series. Along with the class schedules are errata sheets, memos related to specific departments, and lists of closed/discontinuted courses. Beginning in Spring 1995, instructions for using the Automated Computer Enrollment System (ACES) of registration appear with the official schedules.
  - Official Schedule of Courses, 1932-2000 (Box 33)
- Student Mailings, 1987-1996
  This series contains mailings to students from the University, departments, and campus organizations. The Registrar's office received student mailings to monitor inappropriate use of university mailing lists.
  - Student Mailings, 1987-1991 (Box 51)
  - Student Mailings, 1993-1996 (Box 34)
- Student transcripts (microfilm),circa 1939-1969
  This series consists of student transcripts on 73 rolls of 16mm microfilm. The transcripts are arranged alphabetically and by school. This box is restricted in conjunction with FERPA regulations; only the University Registrar's office has access to these records. Two unidentified 7-inch reels of audio tape are present as well. An inventory is available. Please contact Archives staff for more information.
  - Microfilmed transcripts, circa 1939-1969 (Box 35)
Separated Material
Trinity Park High School, Vol. 3, 1915-1921 moved to Trinity Park School Collection, 1898-1922